(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-29T16:34:31.717544",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Are you ready? Let's have a game!
Dang it.
What's going on?
Where... where am I?
No way, did I get sucked into the game world?
What do I do? Hello? Hello?
Why are there so many eyes on me?
Hello? Hello? You're not saying anything.
Oh, I have to get back! Today is such an important day, I can't get stuck in here!
What should I do? I guess I have to figure this out on my own.
There are so many people looking at me. Are those pebbles? Hello?
Are you expecting me to do something? Maybe I should sing and dance, because this looks like a stage. Maybe—
Wait, how do I get out?
Okay...
Okay, I got it then, I'm going to sing and dance a song right now!
Here we go! This game!
回り続ける歯車には成下がりしない
These spinning cogs show no sign of stopping
平均演じる誕生から始まった地獄
A hell that started from acting average
遊び半分で神が導いた盤上の世界
The world on a board led by God playfully
no no no game no life
ぬるい平穏をばっさり切り捨てて
Slash away the lukewarm peace
栄光への階段に存在刻むんだ
Engrave our existence on the stairs to glory
目に映るのは完全勝利の運命
What is reflected in our eyes is complete victory
何もかも計算どおり
Everything is going according to plan
変えてやる 染まらない空白で
We'll change it with an unstained blank space
We are maverick
救済なんていらない
We don't need any salvation
どんな理不尽 襲おうとも
No matter what kind of absurdity attacks us
勝てばいいだけの話だろう
It's simple, all we have to do is win
駆け引きと 才能が 無敗誘う
Strategy and talent invite an undefeated streak
生まれ直した命で 楽しむさ
Enjoying it with a reborn life
二人だけは 二人信じている
Only the two of us believe in each other
心に潜む闇より 強い相手はいない
There is no stronger opponent than the darkness in our hearts
挫けぬ限り そこに敗北は有り得ない
As long as we don't yield, defeat is impossible
上辺の個性で 安心と引き換えに
Trading peace of mind for superficial individuality
プライド殺すな
Don't kill your pride
no no no sense of life
野蛮な雑音を きっかり蹴飛ばして
Kick aside all the barbaric noises
誰より純粋な 声上げるんだ
Raise a voice purer than anyone else
戦うことは きっと間違いじゃない
Fighting is surely not a mistake
手応えが 教えてくれた
The response has taught us so
全て失っても 勝ち残れ
Even if we lose everything, we'll win through
We are maverick
救済なんていらない
We don't need any salvation
どんな理不尽 襲おうとも
No matter what kind of absurdity attacks us
勝てばいいだけの話だろう
It's simple, all we have to do is win
駆け引きと 才能が 無敗誘う
Strategy and talent invite an undefeated streak
生まれ直した命で 楽しむさ
Enjoying it with a reborn life
この世界 手にして 笑うんだ
Taking this world in our hands and smiling
We are maverick
最強の maverick gamers
The strongest maverick gamers
空白ならば 何者にもなれる
If we're blank, we can become anything
二人だけは 二人信じている
Only the two of us believe in each other
戦うことは きっと間違いじゃない
Fighting is surely not a mistake
手応えが 教えてくれた
The response has taught us so
全て失っても 勝ち残れ
Even if we lose everything, we'll win through
We are maverick
救済なんていらない
We don't need any salvation
どんな理不尽 襲おうとも
No matter what kind of absurdity attacks us
勝てばいいだけの話だろう
It's simple, all we have to do is win
駆け引きと 才能が 無敗誘う
Strategy and talent invite an undefeated streak
生まれ直した命で 楽しむさ
Enjoying it with a reborn life
自分だけを自分 信じてる
Believing only in ourselves
深い闇に潜む 強い相手はない
There is no stronger opponent than the darkness in our hearts
挫けぬ限り そこに敗北は有り得ない
As long as we don't yield, defeat is impossible
上辺の個性で 安心と引き換えに
Trading peace of mind for superficial individuality
プライド殺すな
Don't kill your pride
no no no sense of life
野蛮な雑音を きっかり蹴飛ばして
Kick aside all the barbaric noises
誰より純粋な 声上げるんだ
Raise a voice purer than anyone else
戦うことは きっと間違いじゃない
Fighting is surely not a mistake
手応えが 教えてくれた
The response has taught us so
全て失っても 勝ち残れ
Even if we lose everything, we'll win through
We are maverick
救済なんていらない
We don't need any salvation
どんな理不尽 襲おうとも
No matter what kind of absurdity attacks us
勝てばいいだけの話だろう
It's simple, all we have to do is win
迷わない 選ばれし者の 泥のぬぼれでも
Even if we're mud-born of the chosen ones who don't hesitate
誇らしく 生き抜くための 方法を一つ知らないから
Because we only know one way to survive with pride
We are maverick
救済なんていらない
We don't need any salvation
どんな理不尽 襲おうとも
No matter what kind of absurdity attacks us
勝てばいいだけの話だろう
It's simple, all we have to do is win
駆け引きと 才能が 無敗誘う
Strategy and talent invite an undefeated streak
生まれ直した命で 楽しむさ
Enjoying it with a reborn life
自分だけを自分 信じてる
Believing only in ourselves
深い闇に潜む 強い相手はない
There is no stronger opponent than the darkness in our hearts
挫けぬ限り そこに敗北は有り得ない
As long as we don't yield, defeat is impossible
この世界 手にして 笑うんだ
Taking this world in our hands and smiling
We are maverick
最強の maverick gamers
The strongest maverick gamers
空白ならば 何者にもなれる
If we're blank, we can become anything
二人だけは 二人信じている
Only the two of us believe in each other
自分だけを自分 信じてる
Believing only in ourselves
二人だけは 二人信じている
Only the two of us believe in each other
Yeah! How was that? That was the best performance ever, right?
Yeah! How was that?
That was the best performance ever, right?
Hey, over there! You liked it, right? Hey!
Hey, over there!
You liked it, right? Hey!
With this, I should be able to get back to my own world.
With this, I should be able
to get back to my own world.
All right, I'm ready! Beam me up, pebbles!
All right, I'm ready!
Beam me up, pebbles!
Aww, why is it stuck?
Coin, coin, where are you going?
Well, according to video game logic, this must mean I must now go on an epic quest to find the coin or something.
Well, according to video game logic,
this must mean I must go on an epic quest.
I need the coins back to get home, no!
Ah, I mean, I came out through there, so...
Ah, I mean, I came out through there...
Maybe this will take me, you know, on my next step of my quest?
So maybe this will take me
on my next step of my quest?
Well, better than being stuck here, so...
Let's go!
Ah!
Am I back in my world?
Coco doko? Coco doko?
Where am I? Where am I?
Mattetayo, Biboo!
I've been waiting, Biboo!
Eh? Robocosan?
Sagashiteiru no wa...
What you're looking for...
...kore? Ah, coin!
...is this? Ah, a coin!
Coin, coin! Kore ga nai to moto no sekai ni modorenai desho?
Coin, coin! Without this,
you can't go back, right?
Demo sō wa sasenai. Gēmu masutā dearu bokutachi kara, subete torimodoseru kana?
But I won't let you.
Can you take it all back from us Game Masters?
Eh? Honto? Warui no wa...
Eh? Really? The bad one is...
Are? Eh? Ah, ah! To, torikaku, kono koin ga hoshikereba, boku to shōbu da!
Anyway, if you want this coin,
it's a match with me!
Match? Sō, yes!
Match? So, yes!
Kakutō gēmu de shōbu da!
It's a fighting game match!
Un... Ōrai, i won't lose! Ah, no!
Alright, I won't lose! Ah, no!
L R L R STOP & Dash & UP & TALK B B A B S(tart)
L R L R STOP & Dash & UP & TALK B B A B S
これは私をリモートコントロールする機械です
This is a machine that remote-controls me,
少し歪な形しておりますが使えます
Though shaped a bit awkwardly, it works.
UP SIDE DOWN A B A B B A B A
もうちょっとそとにでられるのにね
If only I could go outside a little more...
どうやってもうまくいかないまだまるとりない
No matter what I do, it doesn't go well.
すわるすわるセットダウンプリーズフィードバックにからだつけてめぐる
Sit down, sit down, set down please,
attach your body to the feedback and spin.
うなりをあげてモーターぞんたいおどるおどるダンシングナイト
Making a roar like a motor,
the whole body dances, dancing night.
マッシュアップリミックスだれにもまねなくあかるくうえをあげてシンギングナウ
Mashing up remixes, raising a bright voice,
losing to no one, singing now.
あのこよりもうまくうたいたい
I want to sing better than that girl.
これがぼくをリモートコントロールでそうじゅうできるきかいです
This is a machine that remote-controls me,
せつめいしょはふんしつしておりませんがつかえます
Though the manual is lost, it works.
からかってるみたいな いつものがお
Your usual face that looks like you're teasing me.
今日はかなり本気だぜ
Are you really serious today?
ほらすぐキメるぜ
Look, I'll finish it right away.
座る 座る oh sit down please yeah!
Sit down, sit down, oh sit down please yeah!
トークバックを頭に差して
Plug the talkback into my head.
回る 回る oh turn it around yeah!
Spinning, spinning, oh turn it around yeah!
ちょっと待って、スタンバイ状態
Wait a second, standby state.
踊る 踊る oh dancin' night yeah!
Dancing, dancing, oh dancin' night yeah!
ジャストフィットなリズムを出して 唸り上げる
Put out a just-fit rhythm and let out a growl!
シングナウ oh アイツよりも高く歌いたい
Singing now, oh, I want to sing higher than that guy!
惚れた晴れたの七色侍
The seven-colored samurai of love and sunshine.
洗いざらい主張する存在
A presence that argues everything out.
思い違いが透けてるアンバイ
The misconception shows through.
怖いぐらいのwktk状態
A state of excitement that's almost scary.
気にしないのがアナタのポリシー？
Is it your policy not to care?
悩んでいてもお腹は減るし
Even if you're worried, you get hungry.
なんだかんだで世間はヘルシー
At the end of the day, the world is healthy.
おきをたしかに ぬるま湯男子！
Stay sane, you lukewarm guy!
いいいいいい いいいいいい いいいいいい...
Yeah, yeah, yeah...
もうちょっとでリスキマ埋まるのにね
I could have filled the gap a little sooner.
どうやってもうまくいかねえ
How can I do it better?
ああもう時間が足りない
Ah, I don't have enough time.
座る 座る oh sit down please yeah!
Sit down, sit down, oh sit down please yeah!
フィードバックに身体預けて
Resting my body on the feedback.
回る 回る oh turn it around yeah!
Spinning, spinning, oh turn it around yeah!
うなりをあげて、モーター状態
Turning up the growl, motor state.
踊る 踊る oh dancin' night yeah!
Dancing, dancing, oh dancin' night yeah!
マッシュアップでもれなく上がる声を上げて
Even with a mashup, I'm rising up!
シングナウ oh アイコみたいな瞳になりたい
Singing now, oh, I want to be a person like that girl!
座る 座る oh sit down please yeah!
Sit down, sit down, oh sit down please yeah!
回る 回る oh turn it around yeah!
Spinning, spinning, oh turn it around yeah!
踊る 踊る oh dancin' night yeah!
Dancing, dancing, oh dancin' night yeah!
声を上げて シングナウ oh アイコみたいな瞳になりたい
Raise your voice, singing now, oh, I want to be a person like that girl!
Woohoo! I win!
Ah! Coin! Yay!
Hey, Roboco-san?
Go to the next stage? Wait, be careful!
次のゲームマスターは僕のようにはいかないぞ、No easy.
The next game master won't be as easy as me. No easy!
えっ、大丈夫だよ！ビーブだから！
Eh, it's fine! I'm Pebble!
ありがとう先輩、じゃあバイバイ！
Thanks, senpai. Well then, bye-bye!
バイバイバイバイ！Congratulations!
Bye-bye, bye-bye! Congratulations!
うわあ！
Whoa!
Now then, where to next, I wonder?
We've been waiting for you, Pebble.
Huh? IRyS? Ina?
I'm assuming this is what you're looking for, right?
Yes, yes, I need that! Give it here!
You'll have to race us for it.
Where are you putting that? I'm putting it back in my pocket.
If you want it, you have to beat us. Are you ready to battle?
Fine! I'll be cool too. Watch this. I will always!
No one can dull my shine tonight, no one can dull my shine.
No one can dull my shine tonight
No one can dull my shine
Save me, I think I'm freezing up,
so cold inside
Save me, I need a guiding touch in these dark times
Inside the maze of your heart, I'm the soul that strays
But baby look at me, you're not blind
Oh, can't you see that I can be refined
Your heart is super hot right now, it's time to be your diamond girlfriend
Overheating love machine
Burning hot! Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me
Let them light the way
Overheating love machine
Burning hot! Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
On the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul, break it all, break it all, break it all
The diamond girlfriend,
しとやかなキャラ豹変
ビートまとい
まき散らすのは
ブリンブリンのsparkleだ
Just heat it and wheel it,
make the sword, バッチリ
まぶしさで目が眩むgem
Trust me, your weary eyes betray what you've tried to hide
Trust me, I'll never shy away from your dark side
Under the pressure and fire, see these ashes reborn
Let me show you who I really am
In the name of love, I'll be a gem, ah
Your heart is super hot right now, it's time, I'll be your diamond girlfriend
Overheating love machine
Burning hot! Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me
Let them light the way
Overheating love machine
Burning hot! Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
On the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul, break it all, break it all, break it all
No one can dull my shine tonight
No one can dull my shine
Now "C" is your atomic symbol
ぐるぐる回せ
真っ赤っ赤になるまでwimble
愛が足りないとか闇が深いほど
価値ふえるgem
扱うI'm a jeweler, さあ踊りなさい
Shine on, shine bright, light my flame
Until it all melts away
Overheating love machine
Burning hot! Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me
Let them light the way
Overheating love machine
Burning hot! Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
On the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul, break it all, break it all, break it all
No one can dull my shine tonight
No one can dull my shine
言い訳だー! ウッホー! ウッホー!
Are you guys okay?
That hit you too hard?
Get damn it!
I got the coin! I'm the winner!
I win! Yay!
By the way, where did the coin come from, I wish?
Uh, um, it - don't worry about it.
It came from my Nephilim pocket!
Ah, the world is spinning...
I'm dizzy...
This is a puzzle stage!
Hey, I'm ready for my next challenge!
Now, hey, come on! Hey!
は？
Huh?
There's no game master this time?
え？
Huh?
Well, I guess I could use a break or something, then.
Hmm, maybe I'll dance and sing by myself, you know, as a refresher. Yeah, so I'll be ready for the next challenge.
This is a puzzle stage, so it does remind me of a certain song.
Hey! Everyone over there, you want to hear it too, right?
Yeah?
Okay, wait, I didn't say anything, I'm just talking to myself.
Well, all right, then. Let's dance! Tetris!
どうしてすぐ知ってしてしまうの
How'd you guess it right from the get go?
共振で苦しんでしっぺ返し
Suffering as I wait for a combo
更新で降る隕石抹消可？
"Can I clear a line with a mino piece?"
悪くない
You're not bad, at least
興味ねえ速イハデ感動
I'm not interested in salvation
常備ねえ薬食べバッド
Don't want to take bad medication
超hideeフル見た目暗号か？
"Are there secret moves that are encrypted?"
金に依る
Money's restricted
常識ねえ狂いっパで乱闘
Common sense all gone; it's a fist fight
放置ゲする陰キャでバンド
Banded gamers stay right out of my sight
送信で苦しい駄目cancelは？
"Why is it so hard to respond to mail?"
草生える
Touch some grass, or fail
どうしてすぐ見てしてしまうの
How'd you see it right from the get go?
どうしてすぐ言ってしてしまうの
How'd you say it faster and then slow?
どうしてすぐ壊れてしまうのかな
How'd you break it off just so easily?
パパラパラパラ
(Pa-para-para-para)
近未来しか勝たん
Only time will tell who wins
ショッピングモールの現代コンピ
The shopping mall's full of computer sims
小窓しか勝たんモンティホールの経費でピンボール
Look through the display window or die / A pinball spins its way toward Monty Hall's eye
オイルマッサージ百分コース足湯付き柚子を添え
A 100-minute massage with foot bath included, too / With a side of pate
テテテテトテト テテテテトリス
Te-te-te-teto-teto, te-te-te-tetoris
どうしてこんな目に
Why did this happen to me?
興味がないこと本気じゃないもの全部後回しで
Shove everything to the side, if it's not worth your time then there is no point in it
知ってることは知らんぷり私とは終わっている
I pretend not to know what I know even if it'll force me to rage quit
恥ずかしい過去知ってる奴らの記憶消させて
Throw all my memories away, making sure to forget any of my past mistakes
迷惑かけてごめんね誰か助けて
Sorry for all the trouble I've caused, I need help from someone, please stop the brakes
興味ねえ速イハデ感動
I'm not interested in salvation
常備ねえ薬食べバッド
Don't want to take bad medication
超hideeフル見た目暗号か？
"Are there secret moves that are encrypted?"
金に依る
Money's restricted
常識ねえ狂いっパで乱闘
Common sense all gone; it's a fist fight
放置ゲする陰キャでバンド
Banded gamers stay right out of my sight
送信で苦しい駄目cancelは？
"Why is it so hard to respond to mail?"
草生える
Touch some grass, or fail
配信局漁船でボール ナイツギールな配信ゲーム 名刺は他のメシ ジャッキングボールでチッチなハイボール
Playing Nightingale on stream for fun / Drowning in highball that's filled with your debts to blame
おてんきゅうこうとよかショクジヅキ はやくいきてててててててててとりす
Head to the hot spring; 4 days long with 3 nights of dining / Te-te-te-teto-teto, te-te-te-tetoris
聴覚安定集中じじじ
My empathy's full of shame
うっとかそうとか忙しくって眠れないわ今日も
Manic or sad it's the same, I'm too tired to even get out of bed today
誰が早く殴ってきててたさててくれてよ
Someone please knock me out, I can't cope and I need this all to go away
人生に健闘健闘買い間違いごんやりとした不安は
Cancel out, can't sell out any of this; life is done and I feel a sense of dread
私のせい私が悪いのよそうだよ
It's my fault and I can't seem to fix all this mess so I might as well be dead
どうしてこんな目に
Why did this happen to me?
興味が出ても本気でやっても全部空回りで
Even if I start to care, I can't help but feel that all of this is meaningless
知らないくせに嘘つき私は終わっている
All you do is just lie to my face when you don't even know the half of it
恥ずかしい過去知ってる奴らの記憶消させて
Throw all my memories away, making sure to forget any of my past mistakes
迷惑かけてごめんね誰か助けて
Sorry for all the trouble I've caused, I need help from someone, please stop the brakes
迷惑かけてごめんね誰かよろしくて
Oh, oh...
What? That scared me! I don't know, this game's bugged, man.
Hey, someone report these bugs, dang it.
Cubes are popping out and everything starts... ooh, design, this I need to meet the devs.
Hey, devs! This game is malfunction.
But I don't have time for that. I got to find the coins.
Oh, I guess that's my cue too. Okay, next stage, let's charge up!
Helicopter! Helicopter!
Oh, oh, oh, oh...
I got to work on that landing.
Oh! Wow, what a cute stage! Kawaii!
Ho, ho, ho, ho, ho...
どうもどうも待ってましたよ、フブキ！
Hello there, I've been waiting for you, Fubuki!
Shirakami Fubuki Joins the Battle! Crane Game Battle
フブキざんまい！
Fubuki galore!
Fubuki wa, kore ga hoshiin da yo ne?
Fubuki, this is what you want, right?
Hoshii, hoshii!
I want it! I want it!
Naraba Shirakami to shoubu da!
Then it's a showdown with Shirakami!
Shirakami no crane game kara hatoshite nigerareru kana?
Do you think you can escape from Shirakami's crane game?
Ee, mmm... Okey-dokey, then, makenai yo!
Uh, hmm... Okey-dokey then, I won't lose!
Doryu!
Here we go!
陽だまり サンサン ココロ は 晴れ模様
Laying in the sun, brilliantly bright, my heart will swell and grow sunny
陽だまり サンサン ココロは晴れ模様
Warm sunlight, bright and shining, my heart is sunny clear
ふたつの 瞳は ひまわりの種のよう
Your two eyes are like sunflower seeds
語らい 重なり カタマリ 絡まり
Conversations overlapping, clumping together, entangling
一緒にいること 絶対 必然
Being together is absolutely, inevitably meant to be
でも あなた大事な夢を描く
Yet you are painting an important dream,
終わるまではずっとそうここで待っている
So until it's finished, I'll be right here waiting.
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
立ち止まらないでね
Don't you ever stop standing still!
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
さあ前を向いて行こう
Come on, look forward and keep going!
でも あなた大事な夢を描く
Yet you are painting an important dream...
星空 キラキラ コンペイトウ の よう
A starry sky sparkling like konpeito candy
甘くて 切ない 想い が 募る の
Sweet and painful thoughts well up inside
抱きしめた 想い は 夜空 を 舞い
The feelings I embraced dance through the night sky
急降下して あなた の もと へ 届く から
And dive down to reach right where you are
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
あきらめないでよね
Don't you ever give up, okay?
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
たまには 電話して
Remember to call sometimes
星空 キラキラ コンペイトウ の よう
A starry sky sparkling like konpeito candy
甘くて 切ない 想い が 募る の
Sweet and painful thoughts well up inside
抱きしめた 想い は 夜空 を 舞い
The feelings I embraced dance through the night sky
急降下して あなた の もと へ 届く から
And dive down to reach right where you are
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
あきらめないでよね
Don't you ever give up, okay?
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
たまには 電話して
Remember to call sometimes
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
会いたいよ いま すぐ
I want to see you right now
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
はぁ ため息が ひとつ こぼれる
Ah, with one sigh spilling over
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
来月またあの場所で待ち合わせしようか
Next month, shall we meet at that place?
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
立ち止まらないでね
Don't you ever stop standing still!
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
思い出してよね
Remember me, okay?
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
待ってられないのね
You can't keep on waiting!
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
さあ前を向いて行こう
So face forward and keep going!
You're lonely rolling star
お互いに いつの間にかの 場所 で
Before we knew it, at our respective places
めぐりあわせし ようが
We crossed paths, didn't we?
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
立ち止まらないでね
Don't you ever stop standing still!
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
思い出してよね
Remember me, okay?
You're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star
待ってられないのね
You can't keep on waiting!
うっ！やー！
Ugh! Yay!
あいわん！いわん！
Hey, wait! Wait!
あれは使っちゃったんだよね、ピュッ！
I went and used that, pyu!
あひゃひゃ、ぼくぼくに、ねえ！あれっ！
Ahaha, just me, hey! Huh?!
コインが！やったー！よだれが！やったー！
A coin! Yay! Drool! Yay!
あ、いや、うれしーの！かわいいから許して！
Ah, no, I'm just happy! Forgive me 'cause I'm cute!
しょうがない、許す！
Oh well, I forgive you!
かわいいからね。じゃあ、次の世界へピュッ！
Because you're cute. Now, to the next world, pyu!
あ、テクルが！じゃんぱいお願い！
Ah, Tekuru! Jump request, please!
はい！いくぞ！ねえ、れっつごー！
Yes! Here we go! Hey, let's go!
かぎ！
Key!
はあ…私、今、すごく上手くやってるわよね。
Haah... I think we're doing great right now, aren't we?
ふふっ、次は何かしら？私、次のチャレンジは…
Heh, what's next? I'm ready for my next challenge...
ふっ、ふっ、ふっ、ふっ、ふっ、ふっ、
Fu, fu, fu, fu, fu, fu,
まだ大丈夫！
Still good!
ピュッ！
Pyu!
初め？うわっ、何？
Hajime? Whoa, what?
これがほしければ、ラッキーと勝負だ！
If you want this, battle Lucky!
マイコイン！うわっ、初めのダンチュに…
My coin! Whoa, in Hajime's territory...
注意ってことだな！
Be careful, huh!
え？ダンス？ふっ、はっ！
Eh? Dance? Huh, hah!
オッケー！じゃあ、ダンスしよう！やっ！やっ！
Okay! Then let's dance together! Yay! Yay!
みんなー！チルノのさんすう教室はじまるよー！
Everybody! Cirno's math class is about to begin!
あたいみたいな天才目指して、がんばっていってね！
To become a genius like me, do your best!
キラキラ ダイヤモンド 輝く星のように
A sparkling diamond, like a shining star
栄光 志望校 なんとかして入ろう
Glory, my preferred school, I'll get in somehow
天才 秀才 トップ目指して GO GO!!
Genius, prodigy, aim for the top, go go!!
バーカバーカバカ バーカバーカバカ バーカバーカバカ
Idiot idiot idiot, idiot idiot idiot, idiot idiot idiot
ちゅ、ちがっ、バカじゃないもん！
Wait, no, I'm not an idiot!
バーカバーカバカ バーカバーカバカ バーカバーカバカ
Idiot idiot idiot, idiot idiot idiot, idiot idiot idiot
バカっていうほうがバカなのよ！
The one saying idiot is the idiot!
バーカバーカバカ バーカバーカバカ バーカバーカバカ
Idiot idiot idiot, idiot idiot idiot, idiot idiot idiot
なによ、うるさいわね！このバカ！
What, how annoying! You idiot!
バーカバーカバカ バーカバーカバカ
Idiot idiot idiot, idiot idiot idiot
紅魔館からバスが出て 初めに三人乗りました
A bus left the Scarlet Devil Mansion; three people boarded at the start
白玉楼で一人降りて 半人だけ乗りました
At Hakugyokurou, one left and half a person boarded
八雲さんちで二人降りて 結局乗客合計何人だ？
At Yakumo's house, two left; so how many passengers in total?
答えは答えはゼロ人ゼロ人 なぜならなぜならそれは
The answer is, the answer is, zero people, zero people. That's because, that's because...
幻想郷にバス無い
There are no buses in Gensokyo!
山落ち意味など無いわ キャラクター立てばいいのよ
There's no climax or meaning. Character settings are all that matter!
元気があればなんでも 1・2・9!!
With energy, anything is 1, 2, 9!!
くるくる時計の針 ぐるぐる頭回る
The clock's hands are whirling, my head is spinning round
だってつぶら目玉 二つしかないのに
Because there are only two round eyeballs,
三本の針なんて ちんぷんかん
Three hands on a clock? It's all Greek to me.
次々問題出る まだまだ授業続く
Problem after problem comes out; still, still, the lesson continues
凍る部屋の中ひんやりした温度も時間も気にせずゆっくりしていってね！
In the frozen room, without caring about the chilly temperature or time, take it easy!
バーカバーカバカ バーカバーカバカ バーカバーカバカ
Idiot idiot idiot, idiot idiot idiot, idiot idiot idiot
だからバカじゃないって言ってるでしょ！
I told you I'm not an idiot!
バーカバーカバカ バーカバーカバカ バーカバーカバカ
Idiot idiot idiot, idiot idiot idiot, idiot idiot idiot
ちょっとききわけない子ねっ、お仕置きしちゃうわよ！
You disobedient child, I'll punish you!
バーカバーカバカ バーカバーカバカ バーカバーカバカ
Idiot idiot idiot, idiot idiot idiot, idiot idiot idiot
霊夢とこの百万円の壺を誰かが割っちゃった
Someone broke Reimu's million-yen vase at her place
永遠亭のえーりんが弁償しに来ましたよ 知らんぷりのイタズラてゐ
Eirin from Eientei came to reimburse her, with Tewi playing innocent through her pranks
結局賠償金いくら？ 答えは答えはゼロ円ゼロ円
What is the final compensation amount? The answer is, the answer is, zero yen, zero yen
なぜならなぜならそれは そんな壺あるわけない 常識超えたところに
That's because, that's because there's no way that vase exists. Beyond common sense,
世界の真理がある 秘密の数字目指して
Lies the truth of the world. Aiming for the secret digits,
1・2・9!! ヘラヘラニヤけながら
1, 2, 9!! Grinning and smirking foolishly,
ゲラゲラ笑いながら
Laughing out loud uproariously
みんなー！
Everyone!
チルノのさんすう教室はじまるよー！
Cirno's Math Class is starting!
あたいみたいな天才目指して がんばっていってね！
Aiming to be a genius like me, do your best!
キラキラ ダイヤモンド 輝く星のように
Twinkle, diamond, like a shining star
栄光 志望校 なんとかして入ろう
Glory, first-choice school, let's get in somehow
天才 秀才 トップ目指して GO GO!!
Genius, prodigy, aiming for the top, GO GO!
管理もお疲れさんってとこにゃ
And good work on management too.
「わかった！」
"I got it!"
「アタイがあまりにも天才だから嫉妬してるんでしょ」
"You're just jealous because I'm a genius."
「せっかくだからアタイの天才の秘訣を、ちょっとだけ教えてあげてもいいわよ！」
"Since it's a special occasion, I'll teach you a little secret of my genius!"
紅魔館からバスが出て 初めに三人乗りました
A bus leaves from the Scarlet Devil Mansion, 3 people got on first.
白玉楼で一人降りて 半人だけ乗りました
One person got off at White Jade Pavilion, half a person got on.
八雲さんちで二人降りて 結局乗客合計何人だ?
Two got off at Yakumo's house, so how many total passengers?
答えは答えはゼロ人ゼロ人
The answer, the answer is zero, zero.
なぜならなぜならそれは
Because, because, you see,
幻想郷にバス無いの
There are no buses in Gensokyo.
山落ち意味など無いわ キャラクター立てばいいのよ
No point or punchline, as long as your character stands out.
元気があればなんでも 1・2・9!!
If you have energy, anything goes, 1, 2, 9!
1億100万 バッチリ！
101 million, perfect!
山落ち意味など無いわ
No point or punchline,
キャラクター立てばいいのよ
as long as your character stands out.
元気があればなんでも 1・2・9!!
If you have energy, anything goes, 1, 2, 9!
くるくる時計の針
Spinning, spinning clock hands,
ぐるぐる頭まわる
round and round my head spins.
だってつぶら目玉
Because with cute round eyes,
二つしかないのに三本の針なんてちんぷかん
having three clock hands makes no sense at all.
次々問題出る まだまだ授業続く
Problems keep coming, class continues.
凍る部屋の中 ひんやりした温度も
In this freezing room, the chilly temperature
時間も気にせず ゆったりしていってね！
and time don't matter, just take it easy!
もうバカでいいわよ 知らない！
Fine, call me an idiot, I don't care!
満身創痍
Covered in wounds
初めてのダンジョンでって、小銭出るなんてなかなかやるな。
Finding loose change in our first dungeon, not bad.
よし、コインを宿お…はっ！
Alright, let's stay at an inn... wait!
いえーい！ I got a coin!
Yay! I got a coin!
Thank you for dancing with me, めちゃ楽しかった！ ありがとう！
Thank you for dancing with me, I had so much fun! Thank you!
さ、アイマス行こ。
Now, let's go.
バイバーイ！ Relax!
Bye-bye! Relax!
待っとったぞ！
We've been waiting!
Amane Kanata La+ Darknesss Joins the Battle!
Amane Kanata & La+ Darknesss Joins the Battle!
え？ かなた先輩？ ラプラス？ What are you doing here?
Huh? Kanata-senpai? Laplace? What are you doing here?
これが欲しければ、我々との勝負だ！ マイコインの勝負だ！
If you want this, you have to beat us! A coin battle!
迫りくるゾンビを全部倒すことができたら…！
If you can defeat all the approaching zombies...!
じゃあ、外すは…しない！
Then, we won't unequip... no way!
Run away, run away, run away, you're trying to fuck right from
Run away, run away, run away, you're trying to run far from
Nowhere to go, nowhere to go, nowhere to go, no road is left to run on
I was born, I was born with horns, demons couldn't shake me up
Bring it on, bring it on, bring it on
Cause we haven't had enough, won't give up the fight
Make it out alive, set this world on fire now
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa
Don't give up, it's gonna be alright, 'cause I won't let you burn out
We gotta make it out alive
Tonight, tonight, tonight, I'm screaming on the inside
I was trying to hide, trying to hide, trying to hide, not ready for this ride
Tonight, tonight, tonight, I'm
screaming on the inside
I've watched, shining a light, shining a light
oh, lady for this life
Got to make it, got to make it, we are known
It's the only way to live
A million to one, get it to go, get it to go
Somewhere I have never been
What's keeping us down
down, down, down
Make it out alive, out alive
Set this world on fire now
out, out, out, out
Don't give up, it's gonna be
all right
Cuz I won't let you burn now
'Cause I won't let you burn now,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa
We're gonna make it out alive
Make it out alive
Set this world on fire now
out, out, out, out
Don't give up, it's gonna be
all right
Cause I won't let you burn now
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa
We're gonna make it out alive
全部ダンスなんてすげえじゃん！
A full dance routine is amazing!
あ、終わった？
Ah, it's over?
しょうがねえ、よし。
Oh well. Alright.
コインをやろう！
Let's do the coin game!
あ、コイン！やったあ！
Ah, coins! Yay!
じゃあみんな、ありがとね。
Well, everyone, thank you so much.
はい、ハッピー、ハッピーバースデー。あ、ありがとございます。
Yep, happy, happy birthday. Ah, thank you very much.
スイミング？
Swimming?
オーケー。じゃあ、さようなら。
Okay. Well then, goodbye.
さようなら～！
Goodbye~!
ああ……
Ah...
くそっ、なんでできないの？
Damn it, why won't it work?
ふう……
Phew...
ナイスランディング、いや。
Nice landing, yeah.
は？
Huh?
お、それはステージ？
Oh, it's the first stage?
多分これは、ええと、プログレスチェック？
Maybe this is like a progress check sort of thing?
よし、見に行こう、どこにいるんだ？
Let's see where I'm at, huh?
は？
Huh?
お、お、私はもう1コイン、でも……
Oh, oh, I'm missing one more coin, but...
Where could it be?
Is anyone here to give me another game or something?
ほお、ほお。
Whoa, whoa.
多分これは、セーフゾーン、私が休憩して回復。
Maybe this is like the safe zone where I can take a break and recover.
That's a good idea, you know, I'm feeling kind of tired, and all these songs have been so baby intense.
That's a good idea, you know, I'm feeling kind of tired, and all these songs have been so intense.
Let's, let's take a break. It's, it's just a nap.
Let's, let's take a break. It's just a nap.
I'll be, I'll wake up. I'll just give you like 5 minutes, okay? Just 5 minutes.
I'll wake up. I'll just give you like 5 minutes, okay? Just 5 minutes.
おやすみなさい。
Good night.
よお、おやすみなさい。おやすみ、おやすみ。
Yo, good night. Sleep tight, sleep tight.
Well come and well met, my brave little spark
How long you've wandered, burned bright as a star
Oh, I have awaited you patiently all this time,
past every fate, now sing with me once more,
share of your life,
far greater than memory, its loss and love words cannot hold,
boundless the tale overflows,
and carries your light out to sea,
remember the rain, near and far beloved,
each drop a blessing from heavens above,
and how as time flowed on these waters became one,
streams, rivers and lakes, reaching for the horizon and far beyond,
they carry onward however changed with each brief reflection, by setting sun
by storm's wake,
'til welcomed home to gentle sea,
sinking deeper and deeper in calm embrace,
loving tides sweep in and bear you down,
should you meet a soul rising surface-ways, with your unbeating heart, wish them well,
deep, dark, far away, I have heard your voice, weighed your every choice,
now our hands join round the meaning you sought,
I'll catch your tears, quench your fears, with joy 'til you near the shore,
where in time, all shall as hope be reborn, ah
hush, love, close your eyes, and in sleep abide,
as sun's distant light, echoes down to dreams below,
know you will wake, on winds rise again,
for this journey's end is but one step forward to tomorrow,
What a good dream.
Alright, let's check our progress then. Um, we're still missing one coin. Where could it be?
I've been waiting for you, Biboo.
You... You're...
I'm Biboo.
Me? You mean my last opponent is me?
Exactly.
Me... You...
You're your biggest enemy, your biggest obstacle, yourself.
No...
You've done well at making it this far, Biboo.
But I don't intend to hold back.
Then I won't either.
This stage is too important for me to give up now!
I feel like I'm losing hope
In my body and my soul
And the sky, it looks so ominous
And as time comes to a halt
Silence starts to overflow
My cries are inconspicuous
Tell me God, are you punishing me?
Is this the price I'm paying for my past mistakes?
This is my redemption song
I need you more than ever right now
Can you hear me now?
'Cause we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
I wish that someway, somehow
That I could save every one of us
But the truth is that I'm only one girl
Maybe if I keep believing, my dreams will come to life
Come to life
溢れる涙
Overflowing tears,
こぼれる命
spilling life.
風は 今も遠く
The wind is still far away.
剥がれる錆びと
With peeling rust
うごめく刃
and writhing blades,
死が潜む森に
in the forest where death lurks—
これが僕の呪い
this is my curse.
約束殺す痛みが
The pain of killing the promise...
キミの願い
Your wish,
最後の夢を捨てた
I threw away my final dream.
報いだけど
Though it's just punishment,
そう僕らは今 ああ無価値でも叫ぶ
so we now scream, ah, even if we're worthless,
この汚れた世界の愛
for the love of this tainted world.
そう僕らは今 ああ無意味でも願う
So we now wish, ah, even if it's meaningless,
ただキミとの時間を
simply for our time with you.
溺れた意識は優しいまま消えて
Drowned consciousness fades away gently...
Cause we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
そう僕らは今
So now we are
無意味でも願う
wishing, even if it's meaningless,
ただ君との未来を
simply for a future with you.
Still, we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
そう僕らは今
So now we are
無意味でも願う
wishing, even if it's meaningless,
ただ君との時間を
simply for the time spent with you.
祈りが許しを得られずとも
Maybe if I keep believing, my dreams will come to life
Impressive.
Yes! The coin!
You who have defeated all the game masters shall be rewarded.
Huh? What is this?
Now, show this to everyone.
Yeah! Hey thanks, but um...
there can only be one!
Hello everyone! We have made it to the final stage!
You didn't think I collected all those coins for nothing, did you?
No, because I'm cashing it in!
With all these coins we have unlocked my new original song!
And guess what? The video is gonna come out right after this!
Good job everyone!
And I'm gonna perform it right now, let's go out with a bang! Rockin'!
Biboo's here to play
yeah, uh huh,
Woke up in the morning
I had a funny dream
I was a stone that had been thrown, no way back, I was all in
What if that was me soaring straight to the top?
Let's take a chance, game on, and shoot my shot
Log in, get good, you mad? Let's cook! Talk beep, get hit, clean sweep!
Now you know what's up, hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo Biboo
Come and test your luck, yeah we comin' in clutch, Biboo Biboo
Skipping stone in flight, take 'em out one-shot, Biboo Biboo
Come and help me fight, get on up, let's go, just me and you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss
Rock in!
Bububa bubububa...
Level up, we go onwards
Aiming for another win
A diamond in the rough, it's kinda tough, you gotta keep on rollin'
The grind goes on and on, no breaks
Seal the cracks with a few bandaids
I'll try over and over and over again
Just one more round, please?
Biboo's here to play
(Yeah, uh-huh, ah-ah)
Let's go
Now you know what's up,
hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo, Biboo!
Come and test your luck,
yeah, we comin' in clutch, Biboo, Biboo!
Skipping stone in flight,
take 'em out one-shot, Biboo, Biboo!
Come and help me fight,
get on up, let's go, just me and you.
Player one and player two,
we'll see this through.
Close my eyes, make a wish,
one more shot, I will not miss.
Rock in!
Lost in this game, I feel the strain,
but I'm pulled back up by your gravity.
Your gravity...
I see the shape, I feel the space,
it's set in stone, carve it into me.
I just wanna be Biboo!
Now you know what's up,
hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo, Biboo!
Come and test your luck,
yeah, we comin' in clutch, Biboo, Biboo!
Skipping stone in flight,
take 'em out one-shot, Biboo, Biboo!
Better hit quicksave 'cause Biboo's here to play!
Now you know what's up,
hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo, Biboo!
Come and test your luck,
yeah, we comin' in clutch, Biboo, Biboo!
Skipping stone in flight,
take 'em out one-shot, Biboo, Biboo!
Come and help me fight,
get on up, let's go, just me and you.
Player one and player two,
we'll see this through.
Close my eyes, make a wish,
one more shot, I will not miss.
Rock in!
Biboo, Biboo!
Ah...
Hello?
Um... I'm still here.
I'm ready to get teleported back to my world, any... anytime now.
Mom?
Take me off, I'm scared!
Hey, this wasn't part of the deal!
Hey! No, wait, what are you doing?
No! No! No!
Hey, listen to my song! Wait, okay, my song's coming out, what do I do?
Rock in! Go! Go! Ah!
Biboo’s here to play
Biboo's here to play
(Yeah, uh huh, ah ah)
Let’s go
Let's go
Woke up in the morning
I had a funny dream
I was a stone that had been thrown
No way back, I was all in
What if that was me soaring straight to the top?
Let’s take a chance, game on and shoot my shot
Let's take a chance, game on and shoot my shot
Log in, get good, you mad? Let’s cook
Log in, get good, you mad? Let's cook
Talk beep, get hit, clean sweep, let’s go
Talk beep, get hit, clean sweep, let's go